人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：阿好  Nonopig  芒果妖怪  didina  大黑  天朝直属
时间轴：烟幕迟迟   GGwhywhy
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   校对&总监：阿好
你被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
联系系统管理员
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
身份不明
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
身份不明
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
政府以为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
关键执行人
我们不
We don't.
失踪
关键执行人
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
状态：纽约警局任职
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第二季 第十二集
西装男  你还想抓到他吧
The man in the suit, you still want to catch him?
当然啦
Yes. Of course.
约翰
John?
音频拦截
主体  里瑟  约翰
会话分析  语言识别
关键执行人遇险
我出不去了  哈罗德
I'm not gonna make it, Harold.
长官  有点问题
Sir, we have a problem.
你要的西装男  我们抓到了四个
Your man in the suit, we got four of them.
全拷上
Cuff them all.
我们有新罗歇尔拿到的DNA证据
We've got the DNA evidence from New Rochelle,
有烧毁的车中拿到的血液
got the blood from the burned car,
多亏了你  还有指纹
and, thanks to you, fingerprints.
他跑不掉了
He's ours.
我不想要你越界去
I don't want you crossing some kind of line to do--
这个
This?
网络数据也删除了
Already deleted them from the network too.
现在我们得处理DNA样本
Now we have to deal with the DNA sample.
怎么了
What's going on?
我以为证据表明这些人是清白的
I thought the evidence cleared these guys.
都太干净了
It's all too neat.
现在我只有一个人能够相信
There's only one person that I know I can trust anymore.
唐纳利  尼古拉斯
联调局探员
卡特  乔丝
凶案组警探
你
You.
我知道你在伊拉克时是高级审讯官
I know you were a senior interrogator in Iraq.
我要你动用那些军事技能
I want you to put those military skills to use.
从他开始
Start with him.
你被判定为"非法武装人员"  依法扣押
You're being held as an unlawful combatant,
依据法律为《授权使用武力法案》
under provisions of the AUMF,
《国防授权法案》和《爱国者法案》
the NDAA and the Patriot Act.
你将会被无限期关押
You will be detained indefinitely
无权请律师
and denied access to legal counsel
直到证实你的身份
until your true identity is confirmed
确定你不会威胁国家安全
and it is determined that you are not a threat to national security.
所以如果你还想出去
So if you ever want to get out of here,
就得乖乖回答问题
you need to start answering questions.
-神奇小子  是你不  -恐怕不是  警探
- Wonder-boy, that you? - Afraid not, Detective.
到底怎么回事
What the hell's going on?
卡特这会儿应该从里克岛回来了
Carter's supposed to be back from Rikers by now.
谁都不回我电话
No one's returning my calls.
是  我们这会儿都很忙
Yes, we're all very busy at the moment.
只有我  小熊
It's just me, Bear.
你们忙  我却在坐冷板凳
You're busy and I'm warming the bench.
拜托  你肯定有需要我的地方
I mean, come on, you gotta need something.
我们去把约翰抢出来如何
Are we gonna bust John out of there or what?
怎么你一说出来  这计划就感觉挺烂呢
Oh, it sounds like such a bad idea when you say it.
现在有另一件事要你帮忙
But right now I need your help in another matter.
我现在把布鲁克林一位姑娘的姓名地址发给你
I'm sending you the name and address of a young lady in Brooklyn.
她要牵连进某件糟糕的事情中了
She's about to be involved in a very bad situation.
你这意思是  约翰在那儿焦头烂额
Let me get this straight. John's ass is on the line
我却要去处理个蠢
and I'm stuck dealing with some dumb--
好  我去处理
Yeah, I got this.
我叫德文・克拉克  开了一家防虫害公司
My name is Devin Clark. I own a pest control company.
我去那里是为了申请商业贷款
I just went in there to apply for a business loan.
就听到巨大的声响  好像是枪声
And then I hear this loud boom and what sounded like gunshots.
我就以为银行遇到抢劫了
So I thought the bank was being robbed.
我往出口跑  然后就发现
I ran for the exit and the next thing I know,
自己被捕了
I'm being arrested.
这无法解释你为什么会在地下室
That still doesn't explain why you were in that basement.
我去做资产评估
I was down there inspecting the property.
我是风投公司的合伙人
I'm part of a venture capital group,
我们正考虑投资那栋大楼
we're considering an investment in the building.
好吧  这位
Okay, Mister...
你刚说你叫什么来着
what did you say your name was again?
霍尔特  文森特・霍尔特  我是律师
Holt. Vincent holt. I'm an attorney.
不管你们这些家伙如何逼供
And regardless of any constitutional gymnastics you people think you can pull,
这事儿一完
when we're done here,
我的律师团会让你们自食其果
my attorneys are gonna shove this whole thing right down your throat.
你被监视着  知道吧
You're being watched, you know.
你沉默越久  越显得你有罪
the longer you wait to talk, the more guilty you look.
所以
So...
先说说你的名字吧
let's start with your name.
约翰・沃伦  我驾照上有
John Warren. Just like it says on my license.
好的  沃伦先生
Okay, Mr. Warren.
你不妨告诉我
Mind telling me what you were doing
周一早上你在那家银行做什么
in the bank Monday morning?
我正在会见客户  我在投行工作
I was meeting clients. I'm an investment banker.
联邦调查局档案搜索
约翰・沃顿
我听到爆炸声  看到楼梯那里冒出浓烟
When I heard the explosion, I saw smoke coming from a stairwell.
我以前当过兵  所以就跑下去
I used to be in the military, so I went down to see
看能否帮上忙
if I could help.
我听到了枪声  然后你们特警队
I could hear shots fired, then your SWAT team
把我按倒在地
knocked me to the ground,
不容分说  直接把我拷上了
cuffed me before I could even explain.
从那时开始
Basically from that moment on,
就把我当成恐怖分子一样
treated me like I'm some kind of terrorist.
我不知道自己为什么被关  不知道你们以为我是谁
Look, I don't know why I'm here, or who you think I am,
我只想回家过自己的日子
but I have a life I really need to get back to.
他们不让我见律师
And if they won't let me see a lawyer,
你是我唯一的希望了
you're my only hope.
拜托  我只想回家
Please. I just want to go home.
联邦司法部
波顿检察官：
我们特写信告知联邦调查局在一项调查中
拘捕了四名嫌犯，希望能调取相关资料，
以确定当地执法部门所查之"西装男"的
真实身份
波顿检察官：
我们特写信告知联邦调查局在一项调查中
拘捕了四名嫌犯，希望能调取相关资料，
以确定当地执法部门所查之"西装男"的
真实身份
追踪孤胆特工的事进展如何
Where are we on the rogue operative you've been tracking?
处理中
In process.
还有个玩家
There's another player at work here.
我要他们出局
I want them shut down.
找到那个特工  让他消失
Find that operative and make him disappear.
我在做  但很难找到他
I'm on it. He's a hard man to locate.
联调局可不是这么说的
Not according to the FBI.
他们认为他是里克岛被关的四名嫌犯之一
They think he's one of four suspects being held at Rikers.
那我就四个人都清理掉
Then I'll remove all four.
纽约警察
NYPD!
把枪放下  举起手来
Drop the gun! Hands above your head!
你说要几个小时  现在都几天了
You said hours. It's been days.
如果你还继续违反规定  我可以轻易
If you're gonna keep bending the rules, I can easily--
我没有违反什么  典狱长  但在此期间
I'm not "bending" anything, warden, but in my time here
我发现了15起以上严重违反
I've noticed no less than 15 serious infractions
纽约市监管囚犯条例的行为
of New York regulations governing the care and treatment of prisoners.
所以你不如先处理好了  再来威胁我
So perhaps you should tend to those before threatening me.
我想把手铐解开
Look, I want to un-cuff these guys.
卡特  他们中有一人
Carter, one of these men
是位训练有素的秘密刺客
is a highly trained covert assassin.
我得让他信任我
I need him to trust me.
我们听到了四个故事
So, we got 4 stories
四个身份都通过了背景检查
and 4 IDs that pass background checks.
要么有个人在撒谎
So either someone's lying
要么四个人都抓错了
or we got the wrong four guys.
如果我没猜错  我们要找的那人
If I'm right, the man we're looking for is backed
背后有强大的私人情报网支持着
by a powerful private intelligence network
掌握的资源足以媲美政府机构
with resources comparable to any government,
他们能够为自己的特工
and they could certainly create an airtight cover
提供天衣无缝的掩护身份
for one of their operatives.
我可不会让那西装男
I'm not gonna let the man in the suit slip away
凭个驾照就过关
just because his license checks out.
现在  克拉克  瓦茨和霍尔特都住在外州
Now, Clark, Watts, and Holt all live out of state,
我让局里去查他们的家和单位了
and I've got agents checking their homes and businesses.
不过沃伦先生就在华尔街工作
But Mr. Warren apparently works right down on Wall Street.
我看我们去查下那个地址是不是
What say we make sure that address isn't just
空办公室
an empty office?
-走吧  -好
- Come on. - Okay.
发件箱  未知号码
有麻烦了  我们正在前往
约翰・沃伦的工作地点
就去查吧，警探
他在这里工作多久了
How long has he been working here?
至少两年了
At least two years.
我从去年九月开始为他工作
I've been at his desk since last September.
到底是怎么回事
What's this all about?
你最后一次见他是什么时候
When was the last time you saw him?
沃伦先生几天没打电话也没露面了
Mr. Warren hasn't called or come in for days.
我担心死了  你知道他在哪儿吗
I've been worried sick. Do you know where he is?
核实她和这栋楼所有人的身份
Check ID on her and everyone in the building.
硬盘  照片等统统拷贝
Clone the hard drive, photograph everything,
收集所有指纹
and dust it all for prints.
是  长官
Yes, Sir.
办公室不错  是吧
It's a nice office, isn't it?
你做掩护身份  还真是滴水不漏
When you cook up a cover, you don't mess around.
约翰・沃伦是安全掩护身份
John Warren is our friend's clean cover.
我们工作时从没用过
We never use it for work.
这是约翰最完整的身份
It's the most complete identity that John has,
也是最贴近他真实过去的
and it most closely matches the details of his true past.
但约翰・沃伦仍然是虚构的
But John Warren is still an illusion,
履历不完整的非真实存在
the incomplete footprint of a man who doesn't exist.
如果我们出了错
If we make a mistake,
或者唐纳利找出了漏洞
or if Donnelly spots a single flaw,
我们和我们的工作将陷入极度危机
we and the work that we do will be in very grave jeopardy.
有危险的不仅仅是约翰  警探
John's not the only one in danger, Detective.
你也一样
You are too.
你真会鼓舞士气  芬奇
This is a hell of a pep talk, Finch.
其他三位嫌犯还以为他们被关押
Look, the other three suspects still think they're being held
是要逼他们招供谋杀
for the murders they were going to commit,
一旦他们发现唐纳利
but as soon as they figure out Donnelly's
其实是在找约翰
actually looking for John,
他们会毫不犹豫地供出他
they'll give him up in a heartbeat.
把这罪名安到他们身上吧
I say let's pin this on one of them.
很高兴我们所想一致
I'm so glad we're on the same page.
我正在查那几名雇佣兵的身份
I've been working to identify our three mercenaries.
如果我们让唐纳利发现
If we can hand Donnelly
里面哪怕有一人有军事背景
a name and a military background for even one of them,
也许约翰就能获释了
it might get John released.
如果不成功  我在筹备越狱计划
And if that doesn't work, I'm engineering an escape plan.
是噢  那你最好赶快
Yeah, well, you better work fast.
也许弗斯科能帮上忙
Maybe Fusco can give you a hand.
麦克风打开
等等  不
Wait a second! No!
我是警察  这是干什么
I'm a cop! What are you doing?
为什么跟踪我
Why are you following me?
你和那些亚美尼亚坏蛋是一伙的  是吧
You are with the bad Armenians, aren't you?
这是干什么  我是警察
What are you doing? I'm a cop!
我是来帮你的
I'm here to help.
-天啊  我的眼睛  -弗斯科在忙  卡特
- Oh, God, my eye! - Fusco's busy, Carter.
麦克风关闭
还是我来吧
I think I'd better handle this.
卡特
Carter.
-你怎么看  -我觉得太真了
- So what do you think? - Looks pretty damn real to me.
不过这可能正好告诉我们
But maybe that just tells us
他隐姓埋名了多久
how long our man's been undercover.
从现在起  戴着这个
Look, from now on, I want you to wear this.
这个无线耳机和我的手提电脑相连
It's a wireless earpiece linked to my laptop.
这样我就能在审讯中为你补充问题和资讯
It's so I can feed you questions and info during your interrogations.
更方便我们配合
It'll help us be a better team.
我们联手合作  把他们的生活
Together, we're gonna sift through their lives
查个底朝天
with a fine-tooth comb.
获取中
获取网络监控档案资料
机密行动
任务  已被篡改
主体  已被篡改
相关人员  已被篡改
地点  已被篡改
激活图像文件分析系统
恢复被篡改数据
任务  未命名
主体  文件中无记录
相关人员  文件中无记录
地点  捷克布拉格
直接从帕特森空军基地的服务器上拿下来的
Got them straight off the servers at Wright-Patterson.
你们只需要找间工厂
All you need is a factory and you'll be launching
六个月后自己的无人战斗机就下线了
your own combat drones inside of six months.
-我的天  -抱歉
- Oh, my God. - I'm sorry.
一定是前台给错钥匙了
The front desk must have given us the wrong key.
知道叛国罪要受何刑罚吗
Do you know the penalty for treason?
看看他们的表情
The look on their faces.
真应该带相机来
I should have brought my camera.
干完活  快走人  行吗
Can we just do this and go?
行  约翰
Okay, John.
我们俩搭档  你得学会放松
If we're gonna be partners, you're gonna have to lighten up.
这是我第一次连杀三人
It's my first triple homicide.
不知道我还应该准备好笑话
Didn't know I was supposed to prepare jokes.
他们不是受害人  他们是敌方战斗人员
These aren't murder victims. These are enemy combatants.
不过也没错  我们是杀手  约翰
But yes, we are killers, John.
这是我们的工作
That is our job.
如果你想把工作做好
And if you want to be good at your job,
就得学会热爱工作
you're gonna have to learn to love your work.
你杀过人吗
Have you ever killed anyone?
你呢
Have you?
玩把戏是没用的  沃伦先生
Playing games doesn't help your cause, Mr. Warren.
-回答问题才行  -很好  卡特
- Answering questions does. - That's right, Carter.
逼他处于守势
Keep him on the defensive.
那么  你
Now, have you...
杀过人吗
ever killed anyone?
是的
Yes.
在部队  95年
In the army in '95.
当时我在波斯尼亚执行维和任务
I was in Bosnia for the IFOR peacekeeping mission.
我们在克拉丹周边巡逻
We were on patrol near Kladanj.
半夜  我悄悄离开大路
Middle of the night, I sneak off the road
想去林子里小便
to take a whiz in the woods.
碰到了一个塞族武装分子带着一袋地雷
And there's this Serb militant with a bag of land mines,
拿枪对着我
AK pointed right at me.
枪瞎火了
It misfired.
所以我才活到了今天
That's the only reason why I'm still here.
我在他再次扣扳机前扑倒了他
I jumped him before he could pull again.
我们在地上扭打起来
We thrashed around in the dirt.
我扭断了他的脖子
And I broke his neck.
不想提这事了
Really don't like talking about this.
继续施压  你触到他的痛处了
Keep pushing. You hit a nerve.
你在军队里服役多久
How long did you serve in the military?
95年到01年
'95 to '01.
我是"老铁甲"的中士
I was a sergeant in old ironsides.
美军中对"宪法号"军舰的专称
正好在911事件前退役
Got out just before 9/11.
七年  时间挺长
Seven years. Long time.
是啊  我爸爸是职业军人
Yeah, my dad was career army.
-你爸爸叫什么  -康拉德
- What's your dad's name? - Conrad.
他爸爸的事可以了
That's enough about dad.
继续说那个死掉的塞族人  那是他的软肋
Get back to the dead Serb. He's vulnerable there.
-这么说你是部队子弟  -算是吧
- So you were a military brat? - Kind of.
我妈妈家有个农场
My mom's family owned a farm
就在华盛顿的夏日镇边上
just outside of Sumner, Washington.
讣告  康拉德・沃顿
讣告  劳拉・沃顿
爸爸在海外服役  我跟她一起在家里
I stayed home with her while my dad was overseas.
我11岁的时候他退役了  回来打理农场
He got out when I was 11, came home to run the farm.
克拉丹附近发生暴力冲突
那你在哪里服役的呢
So where did you serve?
你没问我"老铁甲"是什么
You didn't ask what Old Ironsides was.
陆军准尉  常春藤师
Warrant officer. Ivy division.
在伊拉克和阿富汗驻扎过
Deployments in Iraq and Afghanistan.
我猜猜  97E的
Let me guess. 97 Echo.
你是审讯官
You were an interrogator.
正是
Guilty as charged.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
-你耳机坏了吗  -我在博取认同
- Is the earpiece not working? - I'm building rapport.
这样才能拿到有用的情报
That's how you get good intel.
难道你想给他上水刑吗
Would you rather I waterboarded him?
当然不是  坦白说
Of course not, and honestly,
他说的一切都被核实了
everything he's said checks out.
那么你觉得我们找错了吗
So you think we might be digging in the wrong spot?
不  为了抓到他  卡特
No. To catch this man, Carter,
我追查到中国也在所不惜
I'd dig all the way to China.
其他三个人也得这样狠查
We need to hit the other three just as hard.
但是动作要快
But we need to work fast.
已经有势力介入我们的调查了
Powerful forces have already sabotaged this investigation.
我们得抢在他们出招前查清楚到底谁是谁
We need to know who's who before someone strikes again.
请转身
Turn around, please.
抬起手臂  张嘴  伸出舌头
Spread your arms, open your mouth, stick out your tongue.
-参过军吗  -没有
- Ever serve in the military? - No.
问他去哪里读的中学
Ask where he went to middle school.
你在哪里读的中学
Where did you go to middle school?
伊利诺斯州普尔曼
Pullman, Illinois.
罗伯特・戈达德中学
Robert Goddard.
-你叫什么来着  -德文・克拉克
- What was your name again? - Devin Clark.
-你在哪里出生的  -阿克隆市
- And where were you born? - Akron.
你为谁工作
Who are you working for?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你住在哪里
What's your address?
东66大街713号  公寓门牌5B
713 east 66th, apartment 5B.
-中间名  -本杰明
- Middle name. - Benjamin.
问他生日  家乡  社保号码
What's his birth date? Hometown? Social security number?
11月27日  74年
11-27-74.
福罗里达萨拉索塔
Sarasota, Florida.
4  9  8  0  0
4-9-8-0-0.
3  1  4  5
3-1-4-5.
你的MOS是什么
What was your MOS?
MOS在美军中特指"军职专长"
我说了我没参过军
I told you I wasn't in the military.
那你怎么知道MOS是什么意思
Then how the hell did you know what an M.O.S. was?
你名字到底叫什么
Now what's your damn name?
布莱恩・凯利  前海豹特遣队成员
Brian Kelly, ex-Navy Seal.
你可以宣读他的权利了
You can read him his rights now.
走吧
Let's go.
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
你所说的话
Anything you say can
搞定了  他就是我们要找的人
So that's it. He's our guy.
很遗憾不是
Unfortunately not.
当我们的西装男
While our man in the suit
在新罗歇尔杀人的时候
was committing homicide in New Rochelle,
凯利先生正身处伊拉克
Mr. Kelly was in Iraq.
既然他身份已确定
Now that he's been identified,
公共安全威胁已不适用
the public safety exception no longer applies.
排除一个  还剩三个
So one down, three to go.
下午一点  吃饭锻炼时间
1 PM. Food and exercise.
瞧瞧这是哪阵风吹的
Look what the cat dragged in.
这是这混蛋偷了我的狗
You know, this is the bastard that stole my dog.
老实说吧  他是自愿离开
Let's be honest. He wanted to leave.
你还害我被关在这破地方
Yeah, you're also the reason I'm stuck in this dump.
有什么问题吗
Is there a problem here?
没有  以后再解决
No. Nothing that can't be fixed later.
有人想见你
Someone wants to see you.
你好  约翰
Hello, John.
获取中
获取网络监控档案资料
机密行动
任务  已被篡改
主体  已被篡改
相关人员  已被篡改
地点  已被篡改
激活图像文件分析系统
恢复被篡改数据
任务  未命名
主体  文件中无记录
相关人员  文件中无记录
地点  法国巴黎
两杯皇家基尔  谢谢
Deux kirs royaux, s'il vous plait.
好
Tres bien.
-他们干了什么  -管他呢
- What did they do? - Who cares?
命令就是命令
Orders are orders.
只是想确定我们没弄错目标
Just making sure we have the right target.
他们看上去就是一对恋人
They just look like two people in love.
可能就是
Maybe they are.
也可能他们只是比你更会伪装
Or maybe they're just better at playing their cover than you.
偶尔吻个姑娘你会死吗
Would it kill you to kiss a girl every once in a while?
终于没人了  干活儿
Alone at last. Time to get to work.
无信号
约翰  你夜路走多了  终于遇见鬼了
So, John, your past finally caught up with you.
虽然环境如此  不过见到你真好
Whatever the circumstances, it's lovely to see you again.
放松点  这边  这是死角
Relax. Right here. It's a dead zone.
摄像头拍不到我们
No cameras can see us.
不能让唐纳利特工监视我们的重聚  是吧
Can't have Agent Donnelly spying on our reunion, can we?
我知道他追捕"西装男"的事情
I know all about his hunt for the "Man in a suit".
个人认为  他们该想个好听点的名字
Personally, I think they could've come up with a better name.
你要供出我吗  以利亚
Are you going to turn me in, Elias?
失去哈罗德这样的好棋友吗
And lose Harold as a chess partner?
我的确气了一段时间  但是毕竟  约翰
I was pissed for a while, but the truth is, John,
你曾从天而降  救过我一命
you'll always be the man who came out of nowhere and saved my life.
我希望你把我当朋友
I want you to think of me as a friend,
朋友有难  我乐意帮忙  所以
and when I see my friends in trouble I want to help, so...
想帮忙  就别保护我
Well for starters, don't protect me.
唐纳利曾以为我为你工作
Donnelly used to think I was working for you.
我也不是没邀请过你
Hey, well, it's not for lack of asking on my part.
看见那边那人了吗
See that guy over there?
要我们干掉他吗
Yeah. You want us to kill him?
我不觉得你们可以
I'm not so sure you could.
我的直觉告诉我他跟我一样
I've got a hunch he's a lot like me.
你想帮忙  把他的照片传给哈罗德
You want to help? Get a picture of him to Harold.
既然还有别的玩家入局
If there's another player at the table,
我得知道是什么人
I'd like to know who we're dealing with.
你我携手合作
You and me working together.
令人兴奋啊  约翰
Very exciting, John.
快点  往前两个街区有个警局
Come on, there's a precinct two blocks away.
-不  不要找警察  -好吧  这怎么回事
- No! No police! - Okay, what's this about?
为什么他们想要你命
Why do they want you dead anyway?
这这这  躲这儿  躲这儿
Here. Here. Here. Right here. Right here.
谢天谢地  我现在正需要帮助
Thank God. I could use a hand right about now.
实际上  我需要你的协助  警探
Actually, I was hoping for your assistance, Detective.
我给你发一张照片
I'm sending you a picture of the man
此人跟我们的朋友关在一起
who is incarcerated with our friend.
弗斯科  那帮亚美尼亚人
Fusco, the Armenians.
我想你能否动用纽约警局的资源
I was wondering if you could use NYPD's resources
确定他的身份
to identify him.
他  小菜一碟
Him? That's easy.
他就是那个到处打探考文枪杀案的政府探子
That's the government spook who was sniffing around when Corwin got shot.
好  多谢  警探
Okay. Thank you, Detective.
你能不能帮我们摆脱这群
Any chance you can give us a hand
追杀我们的亚美尼亚
with these Armenians that want to kill--
你有仇人吗
Do you have any enemies?
我确定
Well, I'm pretty sure
镜子后面那哥们不怎么喜欢我
the guy behind that mirror isn't a fan.
逼问细节
Push for details.
找出他不希望你问的问题
Find the questions he doesn't want you to ask.
为什么离开军队
Why did you leave the military?
到时候了
It was time.
是啊  但很多跟你有同感的人
Yeah, but a lot of people who felt that way
在911之后又重回军队  而你没有
wound up re-enlisting right after 9/11, but not you.
到了某个阶段  如果你继续当兵
There's a point where if you stay a soldier any longer,
就不会干别的了
you won't know how to be anything else.
所以我离开了  回到华大攻读MBA
So I got out, went back to U-dub for my MBA.
毕业之后  你在哪工作
And after college, where did you work?
我想想  我待过太平洋投资
Let's see, there was Pacific Capital,
剑桥证券  BPC公司
Cambridge Securities, BPC.
华盛顿大学
你换了不少地方
You moved around a lot.
我比较漂泊吧
I guess I was drifting a bit.
又换工作  又换住处  也落魄了一阵
Job to job, place to place. Damn near broke for a while.
但后来  一个好人找到了我  给了我一个
But then, a good man found me and gave me a...
目标
purpose.
那人是谁
Who was that?
我的现雇主  哈华德・芬兰奇
My current employer, Howard French.
让他接着说
Keep him talking.
我在查哈华德・芬兰奇的背景资料
I'm running a background check on Howard French.
不用担心  警探
Don't worry, Detective.
哈华德・芬兰奇查不出问题
Howard French will check out just fine.
还有  我黑进了
Oh, and I've hacked the link
唐纳利的电脑和你耳机之间的网络
between Donnelly's computer and your earpiece.
不过放心
But rest assured,
只有你能听见我
you're the only one that can hear me.
你跟芬兰奇先生怎么认识的
How did you and Mr. French meet?
他在网上找到我的简历  打电话约我见面
He found my resume online. Called me in for a meeting.
然后告诉我  他是谁  他做什么
And then he told me who he was, what he did.
问我想不想帮忙
Asked if I wanted to help.
信用调查报告
你可以打电话给哈华德  核实我的事
You can call Howard and ask him about me.
他肯定正在找我
I'm sure he's wondering where I am.
出来一下  卡特
Come on out, Carter.
另一个嫌疑人想开口说话了
One of the other suspects is ready to talk.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
好吧  我知道怎么回事了
All right. I know what's going on here.
我都他妈等了俩小时了
I've been waiting two damn hours.
既然你不跟我谈
And if you're not talking to me,
一定是别人在跟你谈
someone else must be talking to you.
去他的  谁也别想出卖我
Screw that. Nobody rats me out.
我的名字并不是德文・克拉克
My name isn't Devin Clark.
而是查尔斯・麦卡沃伊
It's Charles MaCavoy.
你给我豁免权
And you give me immunity,
我就把你想知道的都告诉你
I tell you anything you want to know.
想要豁免权
Can't give you immunity
就得先说你到底干了什么  查克
until I know what you did, Chuck.
先说说你去银行干了什么
So let's start with what you were doing in that bank.
唐纳利
Donnelly.
你去过新罗歇尔吗  麦卡沃伊
You ever been to New Rochelle, MaCavoy?
没有
No.
你是否是或曾经是
Are you now or have you ever been
安塞波  世界战略
an employee of Ansible, Worldstrat,
或其他私人情报公司的雇员
or any other private intelligence firm?
唐纳利  你把我们的底牌都亮了
Donnelly, look, you're showing all our cards.
直捣黄龙  警探
Shock and awe, Detective.
先确定他是我们要的人
We need to know he's our man
才能考虑跟他交易
before we even consider a deal.
你是警察口中的"西装男"吗
Are you the person the police call "the man in the suit"?
你到底说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about, man?
和你一起被捕的四个人里
One of the men you were picked up with
有一名训练有素  独自行动的特工
is a highly trained operator with an agenda all his own.
你告诉我那个人是谁
You tell me who that individual is
就成交
and you'll get your deal.
-怎么回事  -火警
- What the hell's going on? - Fire alarm.
所有人都出去
Everybody out.
不行  我们还没问完
No! We're in the middle of something!
抱歉打扰了  警探
Pardon the interruption, Detective,
不过此时是测试
but I thought now might be a good time for me
我对建筑物火警控制的大好时机
to test my access to the building's fire alarms.
把你的手机放进麦卡沃伊的口袋
I need you to drop your phone in MaCavoy's pocket.
马上
Now.
你名叫查尔斯・班尼特・麦卡沃伊
Your name is Charles Bennett MaCavoy.
你可爱的妻子和两个女儿
Your lovely wife and two little girls
住在德克萨斯休斯顿郊外的豪宅里
live in a palatial estate just outside of Houston, Texas.
你4200美元的月供还得很轻松
Your monthly mortgage of $4,200 is easily affordable,
因为你有620万美金
considering that you have 6.2 million
存在开曼群岛的账户里
in a Cayman islands account.
那账户刚刚被我清空为零了
An account that I've just drained to zero.
那些钱是你做非法雇兵的报酬
The money was payment for illegal mercenary activities,
那些罪行我想你没准备好
crimes that I doubt you were prepared
向唐纳利探员全交待
to divulge to Agent Donnelly.
所以现在的问题是  你要跟谁做交易
So the question for you is who would you rather make a deal with,
联邦调查局  还是我
the FBI or me?
假警报  全部人回去
False alarm! Everybody back inside!
你他妈是谁啊
Who the hell are you?
豁免权文件
Blanket immunity.
你告诉我我想知道的  就归你了
You tell me what I want to know, and it's yours.
这个人  这个
This guy, right here.
搞什么鬼啊
What the hell, man?
有人找上你了  是不是
Someone got to you, didn't they?
什么情况
What's going on?
布莱恩・凯利刚刚在牢房自缢了
Brian Kelly, he just hung himself in his cell.
期间  火灾警报器故障
Between that, this glitch in the fire alarm,
麦克沃伊手心全是汗
and the fact that MaCavoy's hands are sweating now
二十分钟前明明还是干的
when they were bone dry 20 minutes ago,
我不能相信任何人了
and I don't trust anyone anymore.
有人从头到尾一直在操纵调查
Someone has been tampering with this investigation since it started,
所以如果他说是霍尔特
and if he's saying it's Holt...
那就应该是沃伦
then I think it's Warren.
获取中
获取网络监控档案资料
机密行动
任务  已被篡改
主体  已被篡改
相关人员  已被篡改
地点  已被篡改
激活图像文件分析系统
恢复被篡改数据
任务  未命名
主体  文件中无记录
相关人员  文件中无记录
地点  法国巴黎
刚接到下次行动的情报
Just got intel on our next gig.
看起来你需要放个小假
Seems like you could use some leave.
我们可以晚几天
We could be a few days late.
四月的巴黎  你看如何
April in Paris? What do you say?
我很好
I'm fine.
做出决定吧
Time to decide.
你要当什么样的人
Which man do you want to be?
童子军  还是杀手
The boy scout or the killer?
我受够同时跟这种人合作
'cause I'm sick of working with both.
没人逼你  是你自己选的  记得吗
Nobody made you do this. You chose this life, remember?
如果你不愿意  你想当个好人  找份好活
But if this isn't you, if you want to be a nice man with a nice job,
开口就行了
all you have to do is ask.
我热爱工作
I love my work.
好了  卡特  带沃伦进去
All right, Carter, get in there with Warren
撬开他
and break him.
你还没告诉我你为什么离开军队
You still haven't told me why you left the military.
你还没告诉我你是不是杀过人
You still haven't told me if you ever killed anyone.
保持进攻  卡特
Stay on offense, Carter.
别让他控制住谈话
Don't let him control the conversation.
记住  警探  请别太快
And remember, Detective, not too fast, please.
约翰说什么  我差不多都能圆好
I can backfill almost any detail that John throws out,
但我需要时间
but it takes time.
你最后一次出国是什么时候
When is the last time you left the country?
去年五月去墨西哥谈生意
I was in Mexico for business last May,
从三号到五号
so the 3rd through the 5th.
瓦哈卡航空
-你结过婚么  -没有
- Ever been married? - No.
有同居人吗
Live with anyone?
怎么  你有兴趣
Why? You interested?
问他的女朋友
Get him to name a girlfriend,
跟他谈过恋爱的人
someone he's been in a relationship with.
稍等一下  警探
Hold that thought, Detective.
虚构一个完整的人有点难
It's a tad difficult to create an entire person.
需要多一点时间
It may take me a moment.
抱歉  请问还有多少问题
I'm sorry, how many more questions
要我回答
am I going to have to answer?
这样吧  我回答你的一个问题
Tell you what, I'll answer one of yours,
然后你回答我的
then you answer mine.
我杀过人吗  是的
Have I ever killed anyone? Yeah.
第一次是最糟的  凌晨两点在伊拉克的突袭
First time was the worst. 2:00 A.M. raid in Iraq.
他们在强攻了   我必须在15分钟内
They kicked the door, I had about 15 minutes
撬开恐怖嫌犯的嘴  否则判乱分子就要攻进来了
to break a suspected terrorist before the insurgents showed up.
但是那天晚上  清理房间安全的工作没做好
But this night, someone failed to clear a room.
我看见一个持枪的男人
I saw a man with a gun,
于是开枪了
raised my weapon and fired.
直到今天  我都不知道他是恐怖分子还是
To this day, I don't know if he was a terrorist or...
一个在错误时间醒来的普通人
just a guy who woke up at the wrong time.
好了  可以问了
Okay, ready when you are.
你恋爱过吗
Ever been in love?
一次
Once.
艾莉森・韦斯特
Allison West.
名字  艾莉森
姓氏  韦斯特
更新数据
对了  这就是答案
There's your answer, by the way.
什么答案
To what?
出生证明
我为什么离开军队
Why I left the military.
双子塔被袭时  我和艾莉
When the planes hit the towers, I was with Alli
在尼加拉瀑布的酒店里
in a hotel room in Niagara falls.
我那时刚刚退役
I had just gotten out of the service.
但当我们一起坐在床上
But as we sat together on that bed,
看着一切发生
watching it all go down,
我知道我必须回去
I knew I had to go back.
我看着她
And I looked at her.
她一言不发  努力坚强
She was quiet, trying to be strong.
我不知道
I don't know, I--
也许我是害怕了
maybe I was scared.
当我看着她  我看到了另一种完全不同的人生
But when I looked at her, I saw this whole other life.
如果我回到军队就永远不会拥有的人生
A life I knew I'd never have if I went back.
所以我留下了
So I stayed.
后来呢
What happened?
我是个傻瓜
I was an idiot.
让她离开了
Let her slip away.
我立刻就后悔了  但为时已晚
I instantly regretted it, but it was too late.
真有意思  一个决定  改变整个人生
It's funny how the choices you make change who you become.
选这条路  还是那条路
Pick one path or the other.
在银行听到爆炸声  试图帮忙
Hear an explosion at a bank and try to help,
突然就
and suddenly--
这么多年后  我仍然在想
All these years later I still wonder...
如果双子塔倒塌之后我重新入伍
if I had re-upped when the towers came down...
现在我会是怎样
who would I be now?
我们已经审讯几个小时了
We've been in here for hours.
有任何证据证明沃伦的身份
Do we have anything that proves Warren's
是假的吗
not who he says he is?
还有最后一个测试可以做
There's one last test we can try.
这到底是什么测试
Just what kind of test is this exactly?
我的眼线看到雅利安派的
One of my people spotted the Aryans
之前找过沃伦的麻烦
hassling Warren earlier,
如果我们任其发展
so if we let nature run its course,
也许西装男能给我们展示一下格斗技巧
maybe the man in the suit will show us his combat skills.
你疯了么  你会引发骚乱
Are you crazy? You'll start a riot.
把所有警卫清离院子
I'd like all the guards out of the yard.
马上  有劳
Now, please.
怕了么  菜鸟
Are you scared, fish?
来吧  接招
Come on! Get some!
快点  还击啊
Come on, fight back.
够了
He's had enough.
好了  起来  我们走
Okay, get up. Let's go.
你到底怎么回事
What the hell happened to you?
你曾是个好警察
You used to be good police.
但这事一开始
Ever since this thing started,
你就一直在违反规定
you've been bending the rules...
我认为我们的国家正受到攻击
I believe that this country is under attack...
这是不对的  唐纳利
and this is not right, Donnelly.
-隐形敌人的袭击  -你做得太过了
- by an invisible enemy. - You are over the line!
我会做一切我必须做的
I will do whatever I have to do--
你必须做的就是看好了
All you have to do is watch.
把文森特・霍尔特带进来
Get Vincent Holt back in that box!
你的名字不是霍尔特
Your name ain't Holt.
你也不是律师  你是雇佣兵
And you're no lawyer. You're a mercenary.
前特种部队  很可能是三角洲部队
Ex-special forces. Probably delta.
至少你的伙伴
At least that's what your buddies
凯利和麦卡沃伊是这么说的
Kelly and MaCavoy told us.
看  他们很聪明  做了交易
Now see, they were smart. They got a deal.
既然你不愿说出你的名字
But since you won't give me your name,
我只有咬定你了
I can just gitmo your ass.
派克  韦恩・F  我要见律师
Packer, Wayne F. Now get me a lawyer.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
能证明那是你的真名吗
Can you offer any proof that's your real name?
我说了我要见律师
I said get me a lawyer.
只要我认为你会威胁国家安全  就别想
Not while I still think you're a threat to national security.
说吧  大兵  你的任务是什么
Come on, soldier, what's your mission here?
凯利已经说了是你们在银行设置的炸药
Kelly already told me you set the explosives in the bank.
不是我们
It wasn't us.
你刚刚承认了你们是一伙的
But you just admitted you were with him.
我可以定你个共谋罪
So now I got you on conspiracy.
你唯一能做的就是供你的老大
Your only play is to roll up on your boss.
-你替谁卖命  -我不会出卖别人
- So who are you working for? - I'm not your rat.
这回答表明确实有"老大"的存在
A response that suggests that there is in fact a boss to rat out.
去你的  贱人
Screw you, bitch.
那又可以加上杀手罪和黑社会团伙之类的罪
That adds contract killing and a whole bunch of RICO stuff.
你是要交待出你老大的名字
Now you want to give me the name of your boss
还是要我直接起诉你为"西装男"
or can I just charge you as the man in a suit?
这就是你要找的人  唐纳利
That's your man, Donnelly.
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
你所说的一切都将做为承堂证供
Anything you say can and will be used against you.
你有权请律师
You have the right to an attorney.
出人  打开一号门
Coming out. Open on one.
我准备好了  警探
I'm ready, Detective.
我已经把约翰的详细越狱计划发给你了
I've emailed you the details of my plan for John's escape.
你只需要
All you have to do--
没必要了  芬奇
Won't be necessary, Finch.
形势在控制之中
Situation's under control.
对了  你欠我一部手机
And by the way, you owe me a phone.
? The sun shines ?
? People forget ?
? The spray flies ?
? As the speedboat glides and people forget ?
? Forget they're hiding ?
? The girls smile ?
? And people forget ?
在找人吗
Looking for someone?
没有
No one in particular.
弗斯科不来庆祝我获释吗
Fusco didn't want to celebrate my release?
芬奇安排了点事给他
Finch has him tied up with something.
我们两只有一人能逃走
Only one of us are gonna get out of this.
我一开枪  你就玩命跑
When I start shooting, you run like hell
别回头
and don't look back.
不  莱奈尔  保全你自己
No, Lionel. Save yourself.
准备好了吗  准备跑
You ready? Get ready to go.
我只想说谢谢你
I just want to say thank you.
我能撑过去多亏
I couldn't have got through this without...
有朋友陪我聊
a friend to talk to.
那些话里  有真的吗
So was any of it true?
我深表怀疑
I sincerely doubt that.
祝贺你  卡特
Congratulations, Carter.
你刚刚抓住了西装男
You just caught the man in a suit.
放下武器  举起手来
Drop your gun. Hands in the air.
结束了  约翰
It's over, John.
带手铐了吗  卡特  把你朋友拷上
Got your bracelets, Carter? Put them on your friend here.
看吧
See?
我告诉过你我们能抓住他
I told you we'd catch him.
但恐怕这是你最后一次执行抓捕了
But I'm afraid that's the last collar you'll ever make.
我那么信任你  卡特  你却丢弃了我的信任
I trusted you, Carter, and you threw it away
丢弃了前途无量的职业
along with a very promising career.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
是我的错
It was my fault.
实际上  约翰  并非如此
Actually, John, it's not.
你们俩玩的那个小把戏
This little game you two have been playing,
暴露的不是你  是她
you didn't give it away. She did.
现在我需要弄清楚  你到底是谁
And now I'm going to find out exactly who you are.
调阅存档数据
任务  红堡行动
目标  绝密
地点
中情局地下网点
摩洛哥得土安
我们确信五角大楼里有人把一台
We believe someone inside the Pentagon sold a secure laptop
含源代码的电脑卖给了一家中国公司
containing some of the source code to a Chinese firm.
我们要拿回电脑
We need the laptop returned.
-我们要去哪里  -鄂尔多斯
- Where are we going? - Ordos.
这是中国中部的一个企业开发区
It's a company town in the middle of China.
里瑟  你拿到程序包之后
Reese, after you secure the package,
清除斯坦顿特工
you're to retire Agent Stanton.
很久没看到这种表情了
I haven't seen that look in a while.
-还好吧  -当然
- Everything okay? - Absolutely.
给我收起来  藏好了
Whatever it is, lock it down.
我要的不是这家伙  我要的是杀手
I don't need this guy. I need the killer.
获取中
获取网络监控档案资料
机密行动
任务  已被篡改
主体  已被篡改
相关人员  已被篡改
地点  已被篡改
激活图像文件分析系统
恢复被篡改数据
任务  未命名
主体  文件中无记录
相关人员  文件中无记录
地点  鄂尔多斯
听着  卡拉  有些事你需要
Listen, Kara, there's something you need to--
对不起  约翰  我也不想
Sorry, John. Nothing personal.
有什么好笑的
Something funny?
我接到了相同的命令
I got the same orders as you.
谢谢你  莱奈尔
Thank you, Lionel,
谢谢你所做的一切
for everything.
打电话给我
Call me.
-怎么了  -有紧急情况
- What? - We have an emergency.
我把卡特最后的坐标发给你
I'm sending you Carter's last known coordinates.
我们在那儿碰头
I'll meet you there.
伪造  查理  探戈
Apocryphal. Charlie. Tango.
接近  标记  威士忌
Toward. Mark. Whiskey.
你要带我们去哪儿
Where are you taking us?
去安全屋
To a safe house,
我会联系司法部的朋友
where I'll contact a friend at Justice,
弄清楚如何起诉
figure out how to proceed with your prosecution.
没有支援  你一个人啊
No backup? You're going it alone, huh?
卡特  我不知道还能相信谁
Well, Carter, I don't know who to trust anymore.
当西装男  当这位约翰
When the man in a suit-- when John here
第一次逃掉的时候  我就知道他有暗桩
slipped away the first time, I knew he had a mole,
内部有人
somebody on the inside.
当他的指纹不翼而飞
And then when his fingerprints went missing
DNA被换了之后
and his DNA got switched,
我不得不怀疑可能是你
I was forced to consider it might be you.
我得承认  你装得挺好
And I'll admit, you played a pretty good game
但我把他一个人扔到院子时
until I put him in the yard alone.
我看到  你的眼中
And that's when I saw it... in your eyes.
是满满的关心
genuine concern.
他是怎么策反你的  卡特
How did he turn you, Carter?
你要价多少
What was your price?
没要价  只是帮朋友的忙
No price. Just helping a friend.
那你就是被人愚弄了
Then you've been played for a fool.
当了情报提供者  为私人情报
Recruited as an asset by a private intelligence--
你不明白  唐纳利  他是好人
You don't understand, Donnelly, he's a good man.
我们是在帮助别人
We're helping people.
上帝啊  他是这么跟你说的吗
Oh, God. Is that what he told you?
醒醒吧  卡特
Wake up, Carter.
你的朋友只不过是
Your friend is nothing more or less
一个训练有素的杀手
than a highly trained murderer.
那种工作又不是碰上就做
You don't wind up with that job by accident.
那是他选择的生活
He chose that life.
他选择变成那种恶棍
He chose to become the monster he is.
现在你也做出了选择
And now you've made your choice too.
不
Oh, no.
-唐纳利特工  停车  -你是谁
- Agent Donnelly, stop your car! - Who is this?
我是你后座的男人的搭档
I'm the partner of the man in your backseat.
我收到情报你现在正处于极度危险中
I have a source that tells me you're in grave danger.
相信我  我的情报从不
And trust me, my source is never--
你好  爱人
Hey, lover.
想我了吗
Miss me?